现在我们进入函数式编程的一个很酷的部分,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Now we move on to
a cool part of functional programming,
也许你们中的一些人认为我在这里的函数式编程演讲。
which maybe some of you thought the
functional programming talk I gave here.
但是让我们从为什么我们有功能开始吧？
But let's start off with why
do we even have functions?
为什么我们会有它们？
Why do we even have them?
让我们看看为什么。
Let's see why.
让我们创建一个函数10的平方，不接受输入，返回10乘以10，并且
Let's create a function 10 squared,
takes no input, returns 10 by 10, and for
一旦我想要这些函数的确切措辞。
once I want the exact
wordings of these functions.
那么，Ryan，这个函数的确切措辞是什么？
So, Ryan,
what's the exact wording of this function?
函数10的平方没有输入返回，具体的措辞是什么，Ryan，在这里？
Function 10 squared take no input returns,
what'll be the exact wording Ryan, here?
我们要用传统的风格。
We're gonna use the traditional style.
顺便说一句，我应该说，我们将看到一个更加流行的风格
By the way, I should say, we're gonna
see an ever more popular style of
声明和保存功能。
declaring and saving functions
in a moment in a little bit.
但是现在，让我们使用传统的函数声明样式。
But for now, let's use the traditional
function declaration style.
我怎样申报？
How do I declare?
如何保存一个函数的10平方？
How do I save a function 10 square?
我要告诉计算机什么关键字，我要保存一个函数？
What keyword do I tell the computer,
I'm gonna save a function?
讲者2: 功能 威尔 · 斯坦斯: 功能，非常好,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Function?
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Function, pretty good,
好极了。
excellent.
这就是功能。
There it is, function.
我该怎么称呼它呢？
What should I call it?
演讲者2:10的平方？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: 10 squared?
是的，它需要任何输入吗？
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yeah,
does it take any inputs?
讲者2: 没有。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Does not.
威尔 · 句子: 不，所以是空括号。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: No,
so empty parenthesis.
然后在函数的主体里，我们得到了？
And then in the body of the function Ryan,
we've got?
演讲者2:10乘以10。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Returns 10 times 10.
威尔 · 森特斯: 是的，太棒了，瑞安。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yeah, brilliant, Ryan.
Ryan 对这个功能很失望，我可以从他的语气中看出来。
Ryan is disappointed with this function
I can tell already by his tone of voice.
威尔 · 森特斯: 你的语气瑞恩,
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Your tone of voice Ryan,
我不怪你。
I don't blame you.
我们打电话，我们得到什么莱恩？
We call it, we get what Ryan?
大家会怎么评估？
It's gonna evaluate to what everybody?
讲者3:100 威尔 · 森坦斯: 100。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: 100.
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: 100.
很好，但是我们要写这个函数吗？
Great, but do we write this function?
演讲者3: 没有
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
[LAUGH]
威尔 · 森特斯: 我喜欢这个功能,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: I love this function,
这是一个可怕的功能。
this is a terrible function.
9的平方怎么样？
What about 9 squared?
伊森，我该怎么做才能改变这一切？
Ethan, what would I do to change this or
no?
保存后无法编辑函数。
Can't edit functions once I've saved them.
想要建立9的平方。
Wanna build 9 squared.
我走了，我该写什么，伊森？
Off I go.
What would I write, Ethan?
演讲者2: 声明一个函数，9的平方。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Declare a function,
9 squared.
威尔 · 森特斯: 难道我必须写作，所以你和我一起受苦吗
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Do I have to write,
so you suffer with me, and
我们意识到为什么我们有功能。
we realize why we have functions.
我要再写一遍，不过没问题。
I'm gonna write it out again, yet okay.
没有。
No.
说吧，伊森。
Go ahead, Ethan.
你知道吗? ，这可不仅仅是擦板子那么简单？
This is gonna be more wiping
down the board, you know that?
讲者2: 报税表9乘以9。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Returns 9 times 9.
威尔 · 森塔斯: 实际上，事实就是这样
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Actually,
the fact it takes so
把黑板擦干净是我们前提的比喻。
long to wipe the board down is something
of a metaphor for our premise.
这相当于编辑和编写代码，非常合适。
That's equivalent to editing and
writing code, it's very appropriate.
我们要写这个函数吗，伊森？
Yeah, do we write this function, Ethan?
不不,
No.
No,
我们不想重写这样的东西。
we don't wanna rewrite stuff like this.
那么9的平方呢？
But what about, there you go, 9 squared?
我会证实我的小朋友，看看那个小家伙。
I'll confirm my little friendly,
look at that little guy.
所以他很不安，很不安。
So he's so perturbed, there so perturbed.
谁知道呢? 心烦意乱，心烦意乱。
Who knows?
There perturbed, perturbed.
加上一个8平方的函数，125平方的函数人。
Add an 8 squared function,
125 squared function people.
各位，我们要打破什么原则？
What principle, everybody,
are we breaking?
每个人都知道吗？
Does everyone know?
是的，干的。
Yeah, DRY.
不要重复自己的话，好吗？
Don't repeat yourself, right?
这是编程的一个基本原则，写得越少越好。
This is a fundamental principle in
programming, write as little as possible.
而且不仅仅是以每小时一美元的单词为前提。
And not just from a premise
of words per hour per dollar.
但是，从更深的意义上说，我们不想在不必要的时候重写代码。
But, in a deeper sense, we don't wanna
be rewriting code when we don't have to.
因为如果我们这样做的话，跟踪和维护我们正在做的事情就会变得非常非常困难。
Because it gets much, much harder to track
and maintain what we're doing if we do so.
我们打破了我们的原则干，不要重复你自己。
We're breaking our principal DRY,
Don't Repeat Yourself.
那么，我们在这里能做些什么呢？
So, what could we do here, instead?
接下来，彼得，我们在这里能做些什么呢,
Turning to, Peter,
what could we do here, instead,
除了写出一个9的平方？
besides writing out a function 9 squared?
函数8的平方？
A function 8 squared?
什么东西每次都是一样的？
What is the thing that's the same,
each time?
那么，我们能做什么，而不是在这里，彼得？
So, what could we do,
instead, here, Peter?
演讲者2: 方形是一样的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: The squaring is the same.
所以，我们可以归纳输入。
So, we could generalize the input.
威尔 · 森特斯: 美丽，奇妙,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Beautiful, fantastic,
我们可以通过泛化函数使其更具可重用性。
we can generalize the function
to make it more reusable.
我们可以构建一个像 squared 这样的函数，不，我们保存它的代码，但是
We could build a function like squared,
no, we save the code of it, but
我们留下一点代码待定。
we leave a little bit of that code TBD.
具体来说，我们留下了什么样的数据，什么样的东西可以乘以它自己。
Specifically, we leave exactly what data,
what thing we're gonna multiply by itself.
因为他们都是一样的。
Cuz they're all the same.
9 * 9.
9 by 9.
10乘10。
10 by 10.
奇数与其本身相乘。
The odd number multiplied by itself.
如果我可以留下的东西，我要去乘空，直到我运行代码,
If instead I can leave the thing I'm gonna
to multiply blank until I run the code,
我编写了一次乘以它们的代码。
I write the code once of
multiplying them by itself.
然后在运行函数的时候动态地运行它,
And then run it and dynamically at
the moment of running the function,
把它变成10乘10。
turn it into 10 by 10.
把它变成9乘9。
Turn it into 9 by 9.
把它变成8 * 8。
Turn it into 8 by 8.
从字面上看，10是要飞和取代数量，我要得到10乘10。
Literally, the 10 is gonna fly and
replace num, I'm gonna get 10 by 10.
8号飞起来了，我要8号乘8号飞起来。
The 8 is gonna fly, I'm gonna get 8 by 8.
这是我们的前提或共同前提的功能。
This is our premise or
co premise of functions.
制作我们可以编写一次然后再重用的代码
Making code that we can write once and
then reuse again and
不同的值，不同的数据。
again with different values,
different data.
这就是参数的作用。
That is what a parameter is for.
但是等等，伙计们，如果，我们开始吧。
But wait folk, what if, here we go.
参数，占位符，这意味着我们不需要决定使用哪些数据
Parameters, placeholders, meaning we
don't need to decide what data to run out
直到我们运行这个函数。
functionality on until
we run the function.
民众，如果它不仅仅是数据，我们可以留待定在我们的功能？
Folk, what if it weren't just the data
that we could leave TBD in our function?
如果它不仅仅是留下一个空白来填充数字、字符串或者速率呢？
What if it weren't just leaving a blank to
fill in with numbers or strings or rate?
如果我们也可以留下一点代码 TBD 会怎样？
What if we could also leave
a little bit of our code, TBD?
只留下一小部分代码在实际运行之后确定
Leave a little bit of our code only
to be determined once we actually run
功能？
the function?
留下一点我们的功能空白？
Leave a little bit of our
functionality to be left blank?
当我们运行这个函数的时候，填充这个函数？
And when we run the function,
fill that functionality in?
这将使我们的功能超级可重用，超级通用。
That would make our functions
super reusable, super general.
这正是高阶函数要做的。
And that's exactly what higher
order functions are gonna do.
我们可能不想确切地决定我们的某些功能是什么,
We may not want to decide exactly
what some of our functionality is,
直到我们运行我们的功能。
until we run our function.